### Chi-Chung (Alvin), Au

+44 (0) 7598 904316 • alvinau0427@outlook.com • https://alvinau0427.github.io M43 6GN Droylsden, Manchester, UK BNO Visa holder and right to work without sponsorship

# PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Web / Application developer with 3+ years of experience and proven production support skills. Core technical skills include Java Spring Boot and React. Seeking to develop my skills or bring value to an established organization through testing, deployment, and software debugging.

## WORK EXPERIENCE

#### Java Developer (Full-time Consultant)

Nov 2022 - Nov 2023

IBM Ltd. - Hong Kong

As a Consultant Programmer at The Bank of East Asia, I played a key role in delivering new features to the BEA Mall credit card reward mobile application. I contributed to both backend and frontend development, ensuring consistency and efficiency.

- Designed and implemented CMS and Mobile application backend APIs using Java Spring Boot and Microsoft SQL Server, enabling seamless communication between the application's microservices.
- Collaborated closely with the BA team and UX professionals to develop new features for the CMS using Vue.js, effectively translating requirements into technical solutions.
- Participated in daily scrum meetings, ensuring progress tracking, and addressing impediments. Successfully handled backend production releases and analysed production issues.
- Implemented continuous integration and deployment pipelines using Jenkins and GitLab, resulting in faster release cycles and improved development efficiency.

#### **Programmer (Full-time Consultant)**

Oct 2021 - Oct 2022

ICO Ltd. - Hong Kong

As a Consultant Programmer at OCBC Bank, I contributed to the mobile banking application's BAU and production support. The application was developed using Apache Cordova, ReactJS, Kotlin for Android native application, and Swift for iOS native application.

- Devised automated deployment processes, leading to faster and more accurate code deployment.
- Resolved automated application builds with Jenkins and optimized alpha-build using Firebase app distribution, resulting in a 25% reduction in average processing times.
- Implemented unit tests to improve software quality based on feedback from testers, resulting in a 30% improvement.
- Assisted in troubleshooting and logging 80+ vulnerabilities identified by Fortify.
- Managed app shielding on production builds using Promon Shield and successfully published the internal app production on Google Play Console and App Store Connect.

#### Programmer (Full-time)

Sep 2020 - Oct 2021

SmarTone Telecommunications Holdings Ltd. - Hong Kong

As a Programmer at SmarTone, I made contributions to the Enterprise Product Catalog, a revamp of the internal web application for retail store kiosks. This project aimed to enhance the user experience and streamline the checkout processes.

 Developed the user interface using AngularJS and assisted in developing backend services with Java Spring Boot and Oracle database.

- Supported senior developers in implementing features such as the payment feature, which displayed chargeable items in an order, facilitated payment information filling, and generated special handling fees.
- Improved system performance by refactoring legacy code, resulting in a 20% increase in application speed and a significant reduction in server load.

#### PC Field Engineer (Full-time)

Nov 2017 - Aug 2018

HKT Ltd. - Hong Kong

As a PC Field Engineer at HKT, I provided timely and effective IT and server support services to over 10+ Hong Kong government departments. I was responsible for data migration, on-site troubleshooting, and setting up secured tools.

- Successfully upgraded, managed, and maintained a hardware inventory of over 2000+ assets, resulting in more effective asset allocation and utilization.
- Provided prompt support and resolved IT-related issues, minimizing downtime and improving productivity for the government departments.
- Conducted data migration activities, ensuring smooth transitions, and minimizing data loss.
- Implemented secure tools and configurations to protect sensitive information and maintain compliance with security standards.

#### **EDUCATION**

#### The Open University of Hong Kong

Sep 2018 - Aug 2020

Bachelor of Computing with Honours in Internet Technology – Hong Kong

• Conferred qualifications assessment by UK ENIC.

#### Hong Kong Institute of Vocational Education

Sep 2015 - Jul 2017

Higher Diploma in Software Engineering – Hong Kong

Conferred qualifications assessment by UK ENIC.

# ADDITIONAL SKILLS

#### **Programming Languages**

Java, Kotlin, Swift, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, SQL

#### Frameworks / Libraries

Java EE (Spring Boot, Spring MVC, RESTful API, Hibernate JPA, JSP), React.js, Vue.js, Angular.js, Node.js

#### **Databases**

Oracle Database, Microsoft SQL Server, MySQL Server, MongoDB

#### Tools

Eclipse, IntelliJ IDEA, NetBeans, Android Studio, XCode, Toad for Oracle, Postman, Proxyman, Git, JBoss, Docker, Jenkins, Kibana, IBM WebSphere Application Server

#### Language

English (Intermediate), Cantonese (Fluent), Mandarin (Intermediate)